STEVE ROLLINS IUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

coding61.sr@gmail.com

**** 206-940-5274

♀ North Bend, WA

in steven-rollins

greenhornsr

Full Stack Web Developer with over 10 years of prior experience as a mobility sales representative. Tech SQL, SQLITE3, POSTGRES, with about developing quality quality of life & building high-quality experiences for end-users. Eager to continue to grow as a contributor

INTERESTS INCLUDE:

Molding Digital Clay(Coding)!

Combat Sports

Head Coach Basketball

Taught 12+ 6th graders basic and advanced basketball skills and lead parent volunteers, managed game

Flag Football Assistant Coach Introduced and taught 15+ 1st graders Flag Football; organized

I-9 Sports · Soccer Assistant Coach Introduced and taught 8+ kindergarteners how to play soccer

Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, NodeJS, React, Redux, SQL-Lite, REST, GraphQL, Python, PostgreSQL, Less/Sass, Flask, Django, Angular, Jest, SQL

Employment

WA Handyman & GC Services Co-Owner

Renton, WA Oct. 2020 to Nov. 2021

Co-owned and operated a construction / handyman business. Successfully bid and completed many jobs for several customers including fence builds, property cleanup / restoration, landscaping, moss removal, gutter cleanings, removal and installation of paver patios and more.

Lambda School Remote Aug. 2019 to Nov. 2019

Team Lead

- Supported the learning and professional growth of 10-15 Full Stack Web development students.
- Mentored students in the understanding of HTML, CSS, JS, React, Hooks, Redux, Context, Express, NodeJS, SQLite3, PSQL, and other associated concepts such as data types, accessibility, automated testing, etc.

Bellevue, WA

Major Accounts Manager - Healthcare

June 2013 to May 2015

- · Identified and introduced HIPAA compliant partner solutions that solved the mobility needs of western Washington's largest healthcare systems, consisting of more than 500 plus employees.
- Ensured proposed solutions met minimal compliance security protocols, industry regulations, budgets, and satisfied objectives with patient safety front of mind.
- Successfully inked first in market Verizon Remote Patient Care solution.
- Successfully sold and deployed a major primary/redundant communication solution utilized by more than 2,500 users.

Verizon Wireless

Denver, CO

Business Account Executive

Nov. 2007 to June 2013

- · Procurement, expansion, and long term management of prospective and existing customer base for businesses that had employee counts mostly ranging from 5-499.
- Routinely met and exceeded monthly sales quota; achieved 100% or better.

Projects

ghsr-portfolio

Apr. 2020 to Current

BUILT WITH: HTML | CSS | JS | REACT

Independent one-stop-shop showcase project.

- Folder/file structure is built with simplicity and reusability in mind.
- · Developed a ticker, expandable/interactive summary section, live social media links, downloadable Resume, and a streamlined email method.

URL to portfolio site: https://steven-d-rollins-portfolio.netlify.app/

BUILT WITH: HTML | CSS | JS | REACT | REDUX | NODE.JS | EXPRESS | KNEX | POSTGRESQL | PYTHON | JWT | YELP

A remote cross-functional team project tasked with building an application that leveraged the YELP API to produce modified review results based on user sentiment analysis.

- Built application with a fully remote team of 8 Full Stack Web Development and Data Science students.
- 4 days expected time for completion.
- Individual responsibilities included Leading the project team as well as producing the BackEnd of the project.
- · Utilized Node JS and Express to set up the server environment and API; used KNEX to translate JS to SQL and deploy the PostgreSQL Database; also used the API and JWT to validate client-side user data sent to the Backend.

URL to deployed site: https://practical-lamport-cc4fcf.netlify.app/

Chicago Array of Things

June 2019

BUILT WITH: HTML | CSS | JS | REACT | REDUX | NODE.JS | EXPRESS | KNEX | POSTGRESQL | PYTHON | AOT API

- Chicago Array of Things; an ambitious project to allow users to view preferred data collected by the Chicago AOT sensors. • Built application with a fully remote team of 8 Full Stack Web Development and Data Science students within a deadline of 4
 - Solely responsible for working with the Back End to produce a Front End that included a client-side authorization, login, registration, and producing a query interface for the user that would present a graph returned from the Back End / DS team linked to the chosen query.

URL to deployed site: https://chicago-aot.netlify.app/

Education

Lambda School - Remote Full Stack Web Development Computer Science

Apr. 2019 to Current

Coding Dojo - Seattle, WA Full Stack Web Development

Oct. 2016 to Jan. 2017